<?xml version='1.0' encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE book PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.35//EN"
   "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd"  [ ]>
<book lang="en">
    
   <bookinfo>
     <releaseinfo>Conventions 0.9.7 - September 2012</releaseinfo>
     <title>Conventions Framework Documentation</title>   
   </bookinfo>
   <subtitle>Documentation early draft</subtitle>
   <preface>
      <title>Introduction</title>
      <para>
         <emphasis>Conventions</emphasis> is an integrator framework of Java EE technologies with the objective
         to easy the development of enterprise rich web applications. The framework leverages 
         other frameworks such as <emphasis>Hibernate</emphasis>, <emphasis>Primefaces</emphasis> and <emphasis>CODI</emphasis> to delivery solutions to 
         common problems like exception handling, true pagination, helper UI components, 
         internationalization, annotated queries etc... 
      </para>
      <para>
         This guide is divided into four parts organized by <emphasis>Conventions</emphasis> archctectural
         layers plus one part for general utilities components provided by the framework and one more part for <emphasis>Conventions Scaffolding</emphasis> a code generation tool based on JBoss Forge. 
        <xref linkend="part1"/> is represented by conventions managed beans which are wrappers to CDI beans; 
        <xref linkend="part2"/> shows how the framework is integrated with <emphasis>CDI</emphasis>, <emphasis>Hibernate</emphasis> and <emphasis>EJB</emphasis> to provide database operations; <xref linkend="part3" /> discusses the view layer and its UI helper components;
        <xref linkend="part4"/> talks about the model layer and its helper classes; <xref linkend="part5" /> walks throught utilities components such as properties provider, security helper, anotated queries, i18n, paginator and so on;
                                                                                    <xref linkend="part6"/> Demostrates Conventions Scaffold, a tool based on 
                                                                                    <link linkend="http://forge.jboss.org/">JBoss Forge</link> to enable boilerplate code generation for 
                                                                                    <emphasis>Conventions Framework</emphasis>.
      </para>
   </preface>
   
   <xi:include href="gettingstarted.xml" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" />

   <part id="part1">
      <title>The controller layer</title>
      <xi:include href="controller.xml" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" />
   </part>
   
   <part id="part2">
      <title>The service layer</title>
      <xi:include href="service.xml" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" />
   </part>
   
   <part id="part3">
      <title>The view layer</title>
      <xi:include href="view.xml" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" />
   </part>

   <part id="part4">
      <title>The model layer</title>
   </part>

    <part id="part5">
      <title>General utilities</title>
      
   </part>
   
    <part id="part6">
      <title>Scaffolding</title>
      
   </part>

   <toc/>
   
</book>
